NYSUT 'Teachers United: The Rise of NYSUT.' Research Notes. 6174/012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
NYSUT 'Teachers United: The Rise of NYSUT.' Research Notes
1928-2006
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Gaffney, Dennis
New York State United Teachers (NYSUT)
6174/012
3.11 cubic feet
3.1 linear ft.
Articles, reports, pamphlets, correspondence, news clippings.
6304381
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
D. Wasser, June 27, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 04, 2014
Biographical / Historical
New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) was created in 1972 by the merger of the New York State Teachers Association (NYSTA) and the United Teachers of New York (UTNY). NYSTA had been affiliated with the National Education Association (NEA), and UTNY with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). UTNY was the statewide organization whose United Federation of Teachers (UFT), led by Albert Shanker, was the predominant teachers' union in New York City. In joining with United Teachers and affiliating with the AFT, NYSUT also became a member union of the AFL-CIO.
In 1976, NYSUT voted to disaffiliate with the NEA. Some locals left NYSUT and created the NYEA (New York Educators Association), which became the state affiliate for the NEA. In the early 1980s, NYEA changed its name to NEA-NY.
NYEA/NEA- NY viewed association with the AFL-CIO's industrial unions as undermining the professional image and independence of teachers. The two organizations also differed strongly on aspects of the governance structure, particularly with respect to ethnic minority representation, with NYSUT opposed to mandatory minimums. The rivalry between NYSUT and NYEA/NEA-NY in organizing new locals expended a great deal of resources for both labor organizations.
While competition with NYEA/NEA-NY was a constant focus of NYSUT's organizing efforts for teachers, NYSUT was also organizing college faculty members, nurses, and other non-teaching personnel. Once members were organized, NYSUT continued to advocate for teachers' and other workers' rights through contract support and legal services at the local level and political involvement at the state and federal levels, supporting candidates and legislation that protected funding, due process, and working conditions.
NEA-N Y merged with NYSUT in 2006, by which time NYSUT had grown to more than half a million members, becoming the largest union in New York State.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Teachers' union, New York (State); Gaffney, Dennis; New York State United Teachers; New York State United Teachers. Archives
6304381
- NYSUT General Files; People Files (Alphabetical) (Box 1)
  - Highlights by Decade (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    NYSUT information bulletin - "NYSUT/A Retrospective" that summarizes 1960's, 1970's, 1980's, 1990's
  - 20 Years of Solidarity, 1972-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    NYSUT's outline of 20 years of union activities promoting Solidarity
  - How to Write a Memoir n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    NYSTA and Teacher Education and Certification outline; background history paper on NYSTA
  - NYSUT Office, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    NYSUT employee bios - Ivan Tiger, Secretary Treasurer; Kathleen M. Donahue, Second Vice President; Maria Neira, First Vice President; Richard C. Iannuzzi, President; Alan B. Lubin, Executive Vice President
  - Evolution of NYSUT and Education Reform n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Report written by Gail Westover
  - Shacter, Claudia-Meyer, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    A History of the New York State United Teachers: the Merger Story: A Thesis by Claudia Shacter, submitted in partial fulfillment for the requirements for the degree of Master of Arts in Labor and Policy Studies
  - NYSUT Budget Workshop, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Copy of the Power Point used at the NYSUT Budget Workshop
  - Bob Allen Interview, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Transcript of the 'Interview of Robert Allen' by Dennis Gaffney, September 24, 2004
  - George Altomare, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Oral History Project UFT: George Altomare / Interviewer: Renee Epstein, Conducted: August, 1985
  - Barrett, Catherine, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Catherine Barrett articles and campaign flyers, while she was running for NEA Vice-President/President Elect
  - Vito DeLeonardis n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Transcript of an interview with Vito DeLeonardis
  - Paul Cole Interview n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Transcript of interview between Catherine Barrett: President of the Syracuse Teachers Ass., President of NYSTA and Paul Cole
  - Toni Cortese Interview, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    News clippings, interview transcripts and articles - Antonia (Toni) Cortese, 2nd Vice President of NYSUT
  - Toni Cortese Interview-Reform, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Transcript of interview
  - Lynn Costello Stuff-Articles etc., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Transcript of an interview with Lynn Costello, by Dennis Gaffney (June 7, 2004); program for an Annual Dinner in Honor of Anthony Pace (June 6, 1972); photo copies of news clippings
  - Ken Deedy, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Mostly handwritten meeting notes by Ken Deedy
  - Walter Dunn Interview, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Transcript of interview with Walter E. Dunn, both handwritten and typed copies
  - John DiGregorio Notes n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    John DiGregorio notes and personal information
  - Feldman, Sandra, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Transcripts from Sandra Feldman and Ed Janko, speaking about their early days as teachers; copy of American Educator, Winter 2005/06
  - Tom Hobart Interview Merger, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Research notes and transcript of Tom Hobart interview
  - Hobart, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Issue of New York Teacher - April 14, 2005; with an article on Tom Hobart
  - Tom Hobart Questions, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Biographical data and proposed questions used to prepare for an interview with Tom Hobart
  - Manny Kafka, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Emanuel (Manny) Kafka obituary
  - Em. Kafka, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Transcript of the Testimony of Emanuel Kafka, president, New York State Teachers Assn., before the New York State Commission on the Quality, Cost and Financing of Elementary and Secondary Education, Commack, New York, 29 January 1971
  - Kugler, 1972-1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    photo copies of news clippings; United Federation of College Teachers; Israel Kugler - The 1966 Strike at St. John's University: A Memoir; A Life in the Workmen's Circle, Israel Kugler
  - Abe Levine, 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Notes and articles written by Abe Levine: Remembering One of Us; A Message to New Members; The Lasting Legacy of Eli Trachtenberg; Keeping the Union Strong; The Legacy of Si Beagle; March 16, 1960 - When a Dream Became a Reality; The Legacy of Charlie Cogen
  - Allen Lubin Interview n.d. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Outline/transcript of interview - appears to have had coffee spilled on it
  - Herb Magidson n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Biographical data for Herb Magidson
  - Nick Maletta n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    notes and questions in prep for an interview?
  - D. Matousek n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    personal notes by Doug Matousek(?)
  - S. Matousek n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    personal notes
  - Daw McKillip, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    NYSTA-1971 merger letter; NYEA analysis; copy of Common Sense: The New York Disaffiliation; Questions and Answers about the AFT a Handbook for Leaders and Staff; Remarks by Dr. White During Merger Discussion at the Board of Directors Meeting, February 12, 1972; copy of NYEA Advocate; Massachusetts Teachers Association letter about Union Challenges; The Organizer, vol.9; no.2; letter and e-mail copies; NYEA, Status Report (1976-77); NYEA Memorandum about Organization Thrust; National Coalition for Teacher-Unity: Proposal, 1974-75
  - Fred Nauman Interview, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Transcript from an oral history project; Fred Nauman: biographical data
  - Maria Neira n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Biographical data
  - Roger Parente, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Transcript - Interviewee: Roger Parente: Interviewer: Rene Epstein
  - Dick Rowley, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Russo v. Central School District No. 1, Town of Rush information
  - Dan Sanders, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Dan Sanders biographical data; Transcript from Oral History Interview: Interviewee: Dan Sanders; Interviewer: Rene Epstein
  - Chuck Santelli, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Notes and articles on More Effective Schools; Compact for Learning information
  - David Selden, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Notice on welcome home reception for David
  - Dean Streiff, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Announcement that Dean is the new Director of Professional Services for NYSTA; Announcement that Dean will be a special consultant and troubleshooter in the NYCT Executive Office of NYSUT
  - Walter Tice, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Transcript notes for follow up conversation with Walter on 3/13/2004
  - Robert Wagner, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Transcript of United Federation of Teachers Oral History Collection - Interviewee: Robert F. Wagner; Interviewer: Rene Epstein
  - Gloria Weinman n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Transcript and background information on Gloria Weinman's conversations between upstate and downstate teachers at the Concord in 1972 while at the NYSTA's convention.
  - Frank White, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    News article about Frank White resigning as executive secretary of NYSTA
  - Jimmy Wood n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Transcript of an interview
  - John Bailey, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Transcript of United Federation of Teachers Oral History Collection: Interviewee: John Bailey; Interviewer: Rene Epstein
  - Charles Cogan, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Transcript of United Federation of Teachers Oral History Collection- Interviewee: Charles Cogan; Interviewer: Rene Epstein
  - Jeanette DiLorenzo UFT, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Oral History transcript from interviews with Jeanette DiLorenzo
  - UFT-Online, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Paper copy of an online bibliography
  - UFT-1960 History (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Articles from the Tenth Anniversary Strike Supplement/November 8, 1970
  - UFT-Chronology (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Founding of the UFT/The Drive for Collective Bargaining
  - Articles Strike, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    photo copies of news articles about the NYC schools decision to strike
  - NY Times, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    photo copies of news articles: NEA Slightly Widens Stand on Public School Integration; Teachers' Stand Urged on 2 Issues; Fourth 'R' Urged by Teachers Unit; Teachers' Union Loses Appeal to Force City to Cut Class Size; Too Poor for Schools?; Theobald hailed for 2-Year Gains; Teachers Federation Warns on Demands; Teachers' Strike in City is Urged; Junior Highs Held Deficient in City; Teachers Warn of Strike Nov. 7; A City Teachers' Strike; Teachers' Union Votes to Strike; Teachers Warned on Strike Threat; Teachers' Threat to Strike Scored; Union Hindrance Laid to Theobald; City Schools map Plans on Strike; Teachers' Group Rejects a Strike; New Offer Fails to Win Teachers; Education Board Defied on Strike; School Head Sees No Strike Issues; 7 Teacher Groups Join Strike Foes; Schools put off 2 Strike Issues; The Teachers' Outlaw Strike; Teachers Against a Strike; Theobald Backed in Union Dispute; Teachers' Group Condemns Strike; Labor and an Illegal Strike; Theobald Yields on Strike Parley; Teachers' Talks End with No Gain; Teachers' Refuse to Cancel Strike; Schools Hoping to Avert Strike; Teachers' Strike is set for Today; Schools Open; The Real School Issue; Students Treat Strike as a Lark; Minutes Support Stand by Board; Scope is Disputed; Text of Memorandum on School Talks; Teachers' Union Calls Off Strike; Teachers' Union Calls Off Strike; Teacher, 27, Tells Why He Picketed; Schools and Strike; Teachers' Union Sees Only Truce; Mere 'Truce' Seen by Teacher Union; Labor Chiefs Join in School Parley; Theobald Seeks Teacher Panel to Advise on Budget Decisions; Teacher Invited to Budget Talks; Joint Union Plan Urged in Schools; Labor Team Meets on Teachers Again
  - Albert Shanker Conference Center, 1928-1997 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    NYSUT publication - The Albert Shanker Conference Center
  - Albert Shanker, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    copies of articles by and about Albert Shanker; Spring/Summer 1997 issue of American Educator - The Power of Ideas; Interview transcript; Transcript: "Albert Shanker - Teacher Power"
  - Unread Shanker Columns, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Where We Stand; Raising Standards; Where did Charter Schools Come From?; A Nation at Risk -- 20 Years Later; Always setting the standard; Professional Force
  - Shanker Memorial Service, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Transcript Memorial Service for Albert Shanker, April 9, 1997 - American Federation of Teachers
  - Al Shanker Last Stand, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    copy of Los Angeles Times Magazine, December 1, 1996 - Al Shanker's Last Stand
  - Taylor Law, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    photo copies of news articles having to do with the Taylor Law; Twentieth Anniversary of the Taylor Law, remarks by: Jerome Lefkowitz, Deputy Chairman, PERB and Harold R. Newman, Chairman, PERB; Times Union, Sunday, February 9, 1976 - Time to strike for change while the Taylor Law is hot; Memorandum Outlining the Provisions of the Public Employees' Fair Employment Act; Statement of New York State Teachers Association to Select Joint Legislative Committee on Public Employee Relations, February 27, 1969; Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations: Interim Report, State of New York, June 17, 1968
  - Taylor Clips/Misc., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    photo copies of news articles pertaining to the Taylor Law
  - Taylor Laws NY Times Articles, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    The Anatomy of Lobbying Effort; Governor Signs New State Law to Curb Public Employe Strikes; New Weapon for Teachers; Away from Public Strikes; Taylor Law's Baptism; Teachers' Strike - Impact on City and Law; Fines for the UFT; Shanker is Jailed for School Strike; Unionists Gather at Jail in Rain to Protest Holding of Shanker; Unionists Gather at Jail in Rain to Protest Holding of Shanker
  - Tenure, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    photo copies of pamphlets about Tenure: Facts Every Teacher Should Know About Tenure; Tenure: Understanding Due Process for Teachers; Tenure: What it means to you
  - Empire State Federation Of Teachers, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    Agenda from Program 1969-70; List of Area Councils and their Officers
  - Ocean Hill-Brownsville, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Radical History Review - Spring 1994 - "White" Values, "Black" Values: The Ocean Hill- Brownsville Controversy and New York City Culture, 1965-1975
  - Professional Negotiations, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    photo copies of news clippings - Militant Stand Against Taylor Law Urged at State Federation Teachers Conference; Professional Negotiation Rights to Teachers; Taylor Bill Incorporates NYSTA Principles; Taylor Bill Authorizes Payroll Deduction of Dues
  - Buffalo, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Barbara DeMille - A Frayed Collar
  - Rally Against Taylor, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Extermination Threat; Rally Condemns New Labor Law; Public Employes to Protest
  - Taylor-Doherty, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    A Short and not entirely unbiased history of the first fifteen years of New York's Taylor Law
- Chapter 1: UFT; Albert Shanker Chapter 2: 1960s Chapter 3: Jerabek Chapter 4, 5, 6: Merger, General Chapter 4, 5, 6: Merger, Articles; NY Teacher Merger Articles, 1972-1973 Chapter 4: Merger Preliminaries (Box 2)
  - Jerabek Articles, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Articles from Newsday throughout 1971
  - Jerabek, Charles, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    New York Times articles and transcript from an interview; Theater Review Molly; 2 Plays Depict a Troubled Holiday; Man Wo Came to Dinner; bio for Charles Jaerabek; Shift in Holidays Voted in Albany; A Winning Look at Losers in 'Gin Game'
  - Tony Pace, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Articles: Jury Investigating mafia Hears an Islip Republican; Gold's Inquiry Into Mafia Will Call 2 L.I. Officials; Inquiry on mafia to Call L.I. Aides; 2 Officials on L.I. Agree to Testify; Politicians Cited in Mafia Inquiry; Gold Cautioned by Suffolk on Immunity for Suspects; Metropolitan Briefs
  - Jerabek: Duryea/Kingston n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Bio for John E. Kingston; Bio for Perry B. Duryea, Jr.; Bio for Francis J. Griffin; Bio for Rosemary R. Gunning
  - VOTE-COPE History-Lynn Costello, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Report on History of the development of the Campaign Committee and the VOTE/COPE drive
  - Teacher Unity-History from UFT, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    photocopy of the article
  - The Merger Story Claudia Shacter, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    A History of the New York State United Teachers: A Thesis by Claudia Shacter
  - Everything You Want to Know About Merger n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    photocopy of article from NYSTA
  - NYS Education Merger, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    photocopies of articles about the Education Merger
  - Kafka on NEA-AFT merger, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Parenthetical comment of Emanuel Kafka before a hearing of the Constitutional Convention Committee of the National Education Assn., New York City, 30 January 1971
  - NYSUT Merger Files, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Articles - Everything you always wanted to know about Mergerbut didn't know whom to ask; News Release - New York State Teachers Vote "Yes" on Union/Association Merger; Teacher Unions to Talk Merger; Shanker urges teachers unite to defend schools; Unions: Muscle at School and on Campus; 200,000 New York State Teachers Unite in One Organization to Form Nation's Largest Statewide Educational Employees Union; Heads of 2 Teacher Union on 4,000-Mile Merger Quest; John Herling/Swinging teachers; Joint Statement of Thomas Y Hobart, Jr., president of the New York State Teachers Assn, and Albert Shanker, president of the United Teachers/New York, AFL-CIO; Merger agreement reached; NYSTA Merger Proposals; NYSTA President Predicts - Ratification of Merger; NYSTA Delegates Vote Overwhelmingly to Merge with UTNY; NYSUT Press Releases
  - Teacher Unity in NYS n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    A Position Paper by the New York State United Teachers
  - Questions and Answers Merger, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    NYSTA-UTNY Merger Agreement
  - Merger Articles-Cornell, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    numerous photo copies of articles discussing the NYSUT merger
  - Merger Summaries, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    photo copy of The Challenger: NYSTA's Newspaper for Today's Teacher - April 14, 1972; Teacher- Unite in New York
  - The Challenger, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Miscellaneous articles, bios, interviews
  - NYSTA News, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Numerous merger articles
  - 37 Myron Lieberman, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    The Union Merger Movement: Will 3,500,000 Teachers Put it All Together?; NEA-AFT Merger: Breakthrough in New York
  - Long Island Teachers, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Teachers United for Retirement Improvement: At Last - Teacher Coalition
  - Merger Articles-NY Teacher, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    numerous articles pertaining to the NY Teacher Merger
  - Merger Negotiations, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Memorandum from Frank White to Ned Hopkins; Memorandum from Thomas Hobart, President-elect to Board of Directors; Motion of Merger Policy, Board of Directors meeting, March 18, 1972; Press Release-New NYSTA President Calls Press Conference; Memo from Francis J. White to President Hobart; Rationale for Positions; I. Agreement; II. No Agreement; III. Disagreement; Minutes of the Board of Directors Meeting, April 14-15, 1972; Minutes of the Board of Directors Meeting, March 17-18, 1972; Minutes of the Board of Directors Meeting, May 5-6, 1972; Minutes of the Board of Directors Meeting, February 11-12, 1972; Board of Directors Agenda, April 4, 1972; Board of Directors Meeting, April 14-15, 1972; Confidential Memo - to Board of Directors from Thomas Y. Hobart, Jr.
  - Inside Education Kafka/Shanker, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Teacher Power
  - House of Delegates, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Annual Report to the NYSTA House of Delegates by Emanuel Kafka, president; delivered Sun., 22 Nov. 1970; Annual Report to the 1970 House of Delegates of the New York State Teachers Association by Emanuel Kafka, President, Sunday, 22 November 1970
  - House of Delegates, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    New York State Teachers Association, House of Delegates, Onondaga War Memorial Auditorium, Syracuse, New York - November 7-9, 1971
  - Al Shanker Letter to NYSTA Convention, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    A Message from Al Shanker
  - Special House of Delegates-Syracuse, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Handbook - photo copy - June 17, 1972
  - Merger Approval, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Merger Agreement; News Release - NYSTA Delegates Vote Overwhelmingly to Merge with UTNY; House approves merger; members to vote next; Merger agreement reached; 1972 Delegate Handbook
  - Proposed Merger Agreement, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Text of Merger Agreement - Between UTNY and NYSTA
  - Merger Board Meeting Minutes, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    April --- Board of Directors Meeting - April 14-15, 1972
  - Invitation-NYSTA-Nixon, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    photo copy of invitation to the annual meeting of the NYSTA on Nov. 8 or 9, 1971
  - Proposal for Joint NYSTA NEA Projects, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    photo copy -
  - House of Delegates, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    NYSTA's Newspaper for Today's Teacher - New Directions; SEANYS Handbook for SEANYS Delegates to the NYSTA; NYSTA letter to the House of Delegates; An Invitation to: City Editors, News Directors and Education Reporters, From: Harry Krause
  - The Concord, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Photo copies of covers of books used for speech - In Search of American Jewish Culture; It Happened in the Catskills; Borscht Belt Bungalows; A Summer World; Albany Architecture; Resorts of the Catskills
  - Text of Cole's Speech, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    photo copy of resolutions from convention
  - Hotel Convention, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    President's Report - 1972, Thomas Y. Hobart; New York State Teachers Association - Imperial Room, Concord Hotel, Kiamesha Lake, New York, Saturday, April 22, 1972; Board of Directors, Constitutional Convention Delegation, Committee Chairmen, NYSTA Executive
  - Computer Post Merger, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Personnel and NYSTA Staff Press Release: New York Congress of Teachers Forges 1972-73 Program at First Joint Meeting; the New York Teacher, NYCT Newspaper, Published; NYS teacher merger and its impact; Tom Hobart welcome letter; NYSUT President Hobart to Appear on TV; NYSUT Blasts Rochester Voucher Plan in Report Issued Today
  - NYSTA House of Delegates, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Photo copies of photos from House of Delegates, April 1972
  - NEA Convention, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Photo copies of news articles - Education Group Forbids New Merger with Labor; NEA Votes Ban on New Mergers; Blacks Rebuff Shanker at NEA; Merger Issue Roils NEA Meeting; Teachers Vote for Statewide Union; McGovern Tells NEA he Backs Education Unit; An Idea Whose Time has not Quite Come; Shanker and His UFT Poised for a New Showdown with City; New NEA President
  - List of Delegates, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Photo copy of - NYSTA: List of Delegates: on file as of April 7, 1972